start with a circle where the radius is
length R here's an interesting question
how many arcs of length R can we fit
around the circle
certainly one is not enough and we can
see pretty quickly that two Arc lengths
with a length of R is not enough how
about three that looks like it could
almost cover half
we can check that 4 won't do the job
and that 5 won't do the job either as
there's still plenty of circle left over
however when we try to cover this circle
with six arcs of length R That Just
About Does it and only leaves a little
bit if we try with seven different arcs
of radius R it covers the entire circle
and there's overlap so we can fit six
arcs of length R around the circle each
such Arc of length R subtends an angle
of one radian so this means that we can
fit more than six radians in a circle in
fact the total number two Pi of radians
it fits in a circle is approximately
6.28